Mike Urbano

Software Engineering Graduate





mi23ke@yahoo.com



1224 Old Oak Dr., Cedar Hill, TX



EDUCATION

B.S in Software Engineering University of Texas Arlington 701 W Nedderman Dr. Arlington, TX 76019 Graduation Date: 12/14/2019

COMPUTER SKILLS

C, C++, Java, PHP, Python
HTML, CSS, Javascript
Linux, Windows Office
GitHub, GitKraken
My SQL/Database
UML
Android Studio
Web Application Development
Sublime, Atom

SOFT SKILLS

Effective Communicator Self – Motivated Flexible Multi-tasking

Team Oriented

Complaint Handling Resolution

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Self-motivated and dedicated professional with over 20 years of experience in the workforce. Multiple years of experience working on a team to achieve common goals. Over 5 total years of management experience. Excel at interfacing with others at all levels of management to ensure organizational goals are attained. Strong oral /written communication, problem solving and organizational skills.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mike-urbano-2ba71a179/

EXPERIENCE

Citi Cards/Home Depot | Irving, TX

Credit Officer 1

08/2015 - 12/2017

- Use credit policy to underwrite credit loan requests up to \$100K
- Stay current on applicable training materials
- Manage workload to stay within set timeframes
- Present completed files to upper management for decision quality review
- Work with team members to fulfill contractual obligations to client
- Work with customers to obtain any required documentation

Citi Bank North America | Irving, TX

Credit Underwriter 2 (Credit Delivery)

04/2014 - 08/2015

- Enter loan applications into Loan Path system
- Analyze application package for any errors and/or missing documentation
- Prepare letters to clients requesting additional information

Citi Cards/Home Depot | Irving, TX

Credit Operations Specialist 3

08/2011 - 04/2014

- Underwrite credit requests between \$25k and \$35K
- Process all requests from Puerto Rico up to \$35K
- Analyze consumer and commercial credit reports to establish credit worthiness
- Make contact with client to verify requests

Operations Assistant

10/2007 - 08/2011

- Conduct team meetings to discuss new policy updates
- Schedule trainings and meetings for all teams
- Reserve space for meetings/trainings
- Assist with training of new hires
- Assist technical writer with producing policy documentation
- Assist with coaching team members